In 2021, DeFi option vaults like Ribbon and Friktion did billions in volume.
A year later, they were dead.
They sold options too cheap, leaking value to market makers.
And unhedged, one crash wiped out the LPs.
Picking up pennies in front of a steamroller.
I'm rebuilding structured vaults on Sui, with both of those problems fixed.
This is Squall.
Squall is a structured-yield vault on Sui, and it changes the model in two ways.
Instead of cheap auctions, it provides liquidity on DeepBook Predict's vol-priced order book,
earning the spread from real trading flow.
And it's hedged by design, so a crash can't wipe it out.
Everything you're about to see, you can verify yourself.
Let me walk you through it, as one dive into the Sui ocean.
We start at the surface. You deposit USDC,
and the vault mints you a share token in return.
It's a standard ERC-4626 vault, the proven yield-vault standard, now in Move on Sui.
Mint shares, mark net asset value, withdraw anytime.
No options knowledge, no lockups. Everything interesting happens below the surface.
Before deploying a dollar, the vault asks: what is the fair price of risk right now?
Our keeper, a small off-chain service, reads DeepBook's live volatility surface,
and publishes it on-chain as the Vol Index, the first on-chain volatility index on Sui.
It's smoothed, so it stays stable, not noisy.
That index is the price tag on every position the vault takes.
So the vault never guesses. It prices risk off a live, on-chain benchmark.
That's the brain. Now we go deeper.
We dive into the depths, DeepBook Predict, our primary sponsor.
This is where Squall earns.
On the right, OracleSVI is the live volatility surface that prices every trade.
In the middle is the vol-priced order book, where traders pay the spread,
real, recurring flow, not a cheap weekly auction.
So the vault calls supply, hands over USDC, and becomes the house,
holding a PLP position that backs the book.
As traders pay the spread, that position accrues value, marked to NAV each epoch.
And a tail hedge caps the crash that killed the old vaults.
Squall isn't gambling. It's the house.
Finally we reach the seabed, Walrus, our second sponsor.
This is where Squall earns trust.
Every epoch, the vault writes a snapshot to Walrus and gets back a blobId.
That blobId is a content hash, so the snapshot can never be quietly changed.
Each snapshot also embeds the previous one's id, forming a hash-chain you can't reorder or alter.
And the keeper anchors each one on Sui, in a ProofLog recording the NAV and blobId.
So the history is complete and tamper-proof: the on-chain log is the index.
To verify, anyone re-fetches the blob and checks it against the on-chain anchor.
Our Proof tab does exactly that, live. Trust by proof, not by promise.
And this isn't a mockup. Here's Squall, live on Sui testnet.
I connect my wallet and deposit a hundred test USDC.
I approve, and I receive my vault shares, vSTRATA.
The toast gives me a transaction link. Let's follow it to Suiscan.
Real testnet: a hundred USDC in, vault shares out, and the object is the Squall Vault.
Here's our strategy on-chain, with real supply and withdraw calls into DeepBook Predict.
Deposit, allocate, harvest, redeem, all verified on-chain.
This gauge is our on-chain Vol Index, reading live.
Here's the same VolIndex object on Suiscan, with the keeper's updates.
Now the proof. These are our NAV attestations.
I click verify, and the app re-fetches the blob from Walrus and confirms it.
And here's that exact blob on Walruscan, by its content ID, immutable and public.
Anyone can check it. Nothing here is taken on faith.
And I can withdraw anytime, burn the shares, USDC back.
Deposit at the surface. Price risk off the first on-chain vol index on Sui.
Earn the spread as the house on DeepBook. Prove every number on Walrus.
That's Squall. Structured yield you don't have to trust. You can verify it.
Live on Sui testnet now.